<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Matt Lebrun</title><link href="https://mattlebrun.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://localhost:8000/feeds/hacks.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://mattlebrun.com/</id><updated>2013-12-21T12:40:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>new year, new home for my domains</title><link href="https://mattlebrun.com/new-year-new-home-for-my-domains.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-12-21T12:40:00+08:00</published><updated>2013-12-21T12:40:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Matt Lebrun</name></author><id>tag:mattlebrun.com,2013-12-21:new-year-new-home-for-my-domains.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Its almost Christmas and the domains I've registered last year are a few days 
short of expiration. Its time to make a choice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;GoDaddy - a brief background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year I got myself several nice domains for a very cheap price at GoDaddy. 
I was pretty much new with buying stuff online and I'm a cheapskate and GoDaddy 
sort of handed me that indulgence. You simply search over the internets you'll 
find GoDaddy coupons all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as I learn more about the domain registration and differences between 
each registrar I've kinda regretted that decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;NameSilo - a new beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was yesterday when I started to take seriously GoDaddy's email notifications 
about my domains that are due for expiration soon. As I checked, the renewal 
cost where really high. What I previously got for dirt cheap (~US$3), will 
now cost me about US$14. And I have 4 of them expiring soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was already considering moving away from GoDaddy after all the controversies 
spinning around the company anyway so this only sealed that deal for me. Time 
to hit the internets to search for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NameCheap was up my alley at this point, in fact I have 1 domain with them. 
However as I looked further, I stumbled upon NameSilo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now NameSilo just clicked with me instantly. Cheap, no upsells, no hidden 
charges, free WHOIS protection, and most importantly registration costs are the 
same as renewals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I reloaded my prepaid credit card and went on about the domain transfer 
process. It was relatively straightforward and about 20mins later my domains 
are now happily hanging out on NameSilo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you're looking into transferring your domains or thinking of getting a 
new one, I highly recommend in giving them a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;promoted links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have here a couple of promotions in case you decide to try them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use this promo code to get a $1 discount: &lt;code&gt;freedollar&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or visit their page with my affiliate &lt;a href="http://www.namesilo.com/?rid=4193c40rx"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; and make me happy :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>the setup</title><link href="https://mattlebrun.com/the-setup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-06-11T23:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2013-06-11T23:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Matt Lebrun</name></author><id>tag:mattlebrun.com,2013-06-11:the-setup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was browsing the social networks today and chanced upon 
&lt;a href="http://usesthis.com/"&gt;The Setup&lt;/a&gt; which is a website that features 
interviews of people &lt;em&gt;(mostly geeks)&lt;/em&gt; where they get to talk about what 
they do and then elaborate more on what tools (hardware and software) they 
use to get shit done. I thought, "Hey that's pretty cool.", so I read on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I browsed through one interview to the next I noticed that most 
(perhaps in the 90th percentile) are using Apple computers. Which got me to 
ponder whether this is just another Apple fan site. Thank goodness the 
author cleared this out in the &lt;a href="http://usesthis.com/about/"&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; page. I 
was short of dismissing the site as one and hitting the close button. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interview with &lt;a href="http://eric.s.raymond.usesthis.com/"&gt;ESR&lt;/a&gt; was one that 
got me thinking and write this post. Albeit, it was the trigger after a 
spur of collective thoughts that was running in my head as I read on the 
interviews of hackers and programmers that I admire. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in the spirit of the &lt;a href="http://usesthis.com/"&gt;The Setup's&lt;/a&gt; ethos, here's 
how my setup...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;who are you, and what do you do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm Matt Lebrun, and I fancy myself as a hybrid programmer/designer. It's a 
work in progress and I strive to reach that ideal everyday. I speak several 
&lt;em&gt;(programming)&lt;/em&gt; languages but I love &lt;a href="http://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; above 
all. In fact, I'm so crazy about it that I just had to spend a significant 
amount of free time volunteering to our local &lt;a href="http://python.ph"&gt;Python community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I should put this in a separate about page. But since I'm lazy at 
moment, this will do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;what hardware do you use?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you heard of a programmer who does not own a computer? Yep I'm one of 
them. At least I used to be until a couple of months ago. For a long time, 
I contented myself with company issued computers until a life event forced 
me to buy one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got myself a decent &lt;a href="http://www.villman.com/Product-Detail/Acer_V5-431-10072G50Ma"&gt;Acer V5 431&lt;/a&gt;. 
It sports an IvyBridge Celeron 1007U dual-core ULV processor with internal 
Intel HD 4000 graphics. I also bumped up the pre-installed RAM to 8GB to 
make sure my VMs and numerous browser tabs are well fed. It also sports an 
Ultrabook-ish look that's nice to look at. It also had other nice features 
that I don't want to elaborate more on. Most importantly, it came with a 
price that didn't break the bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was happily working on it for a couple of months until the awesome folks 
at &lt;a href="http://www.save22.com"&gt;Save22&lt;/a&gt; got me a laptop of my choosing. I got 
myself a very sexy &lt;a href="http://h10025.www1.hp.com/ewfrf/wc/document?cc=us&amp;amp;lc=en&amp;amp;dlc=en&amp;amp;docname=c03508920#N351"&gt;HP Envy 4&lt;/a&gt;. 
I use this as my primary machine now and have lent my Acer machine to my 
sister indefinitely. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the mobile end, I use the 1st generation &lt;a href="http://www.gsmarena.com/samsung_p1000_galaxy_tab-3370.php"&gt;Galaxy Tab&lt;/a&gt;, 
both as a phone and tablet. I do all sorts of on-the-go stuff with it like 
taking pictures and videos, gaming, journaling, sketching, reading, social 
networking. I even code in Python on it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;and what software?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider Vim my wife and SublimeText2 my mistress. As I play around with 
sublime, the more hooked I am. Is that bad?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used NetBeans and Eclipse once when I was teaching myself to develop 
Android apps. Then &lt;a href="http://phonegap.com/"&gt;PhoneGap&lt;/a&gt; is mature enough, and 
there's even &lt;a href="http://kivy.org/"&gt;Kivy&lt;/a&gt;... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I primarily used Chrome/Chromium as my browser of choice, but the latest 
incarnation of Firefox rekindled my love for it. So its my primary choice 
now on both my PC and tablet. I just had to say that tab groups and firebug 
should be default for any web development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gnome Terminator is my terminal of choice. Split, tab, and theme your 
terminal to your hearts content. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use VirtualBox heavily and run 1-3 virtual development servers at a time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GIMP and Inkscape are my design tools of choice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shutter for selective screen capture. Very important for work and noting 
things down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LibreOffice and Google Docs for spreadsheets and presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UbuntuOne and Insync keeps my important files in the safety of the cloud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thunderbird organizes my Gmail, Google calendar, and Google Tasks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skype and Empathy for chatting and office communication. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google contacts keeps my contacts available on both mobile and PC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KeepassX keeps my passwords, and I got it synced on both PC and mobile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/cr8ivecodesmith"&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; more nowadays. Its just a 
more sensible social network, IMHO. My Facebook interaction is limited to 
the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/pinoypug/"&gt;Python Users Group&lt;/a&gt; and 
posting some family photo updates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux, specifically Ubuntu as my OS of choice both as my daily driver and 
on my VM dev servers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Galaxy Tab is powered by CM10.1 and it works super fine. JB 4.2.2 and 
kernel 3.x breathed new life to this old but trusty warrior. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;what would be your dream setup?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now I'm very happy with my PC. Though I'm still waiting for the day 
where ~1.2kgs, ~0.7mm thick, 500GB SSD, 16GB RAM, ~3GHZ Quad-core CPU, ~2GB 
Dedicated Graphics, ~8hrs Battery, and Fully Linux compatible Ultrabooks 
would emerge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could also use a bluetooth stereo headset with mic that I can use on both 
my PC and tablet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd also wish that Ubuntu could be a bit more up to date with the latest 
kernel and do a rolling release just like Arch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had the budget, I'd get something like a Galaxy Note 2 or Nexus 4. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>