<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>programmers are people too</title><link href="http://mattlebrun.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://mattlebrun.com/feeds/life.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://mattlebrun.com/</id><updated>2014-01-24T03:04:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>4 weeks to fitness experiment - week 2</title><link href="http://mattlebrun.com/4-weeks-to-fitness-experiment-week-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-24T03:04:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:mattlebrun.com,2014-01-24:4-weeks-to-fitness-experiment-week-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The stats I'm showing is basically my stats at the start of the week. Or putting
it in another way, its the stats that resulted from my previous week's effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wasn't able to get the upper body workout experience properly because I've got 
no equipment. I'm seriousy considering getting exercise bands as their more 
portable and easily stored than a set of dumbells so I can maximize their 
benefits. They're best to best for building tone and muscle endurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;week 2 experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My week 2 workout actually started &lt;em&gt;officially&lt;/em&gt; on the 3rd week of January because 
I got inflicted with the flu on the second week. So I guess this 4-week program 
will have to span upto the 1st week of February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dramatic weight loss - probably water weight?
Developed toned legs. Quads and calves are definitely more defined.
Pilates exercises are crazy difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;week 2 stats &lt;em&gt;(Jan 20-24, 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weight: 65.7kg&lt;br /&gt;
Neck: 36.7cm&lt;br /&gt;
Waist: 87.5cm  &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="fitness"></category></entry><entry><title>4 weeks to fitness experiment - week 1</title><link href="http://mattlebrun.com/4-weeks-to-fitness-experiment-week-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-24T02:41:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:mattlebrun.com,2014-01-24:4-weeks-to-fitness-experiment-week-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well I did say I'll &lt;em&gt;try&lt;/em&gt; to give a weekly update. Anyway no excuses here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started the program that I talked about previously last January 6 so that 
it falls on a Monday. I was very excited to get my first week rolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;week 1 experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any self-respecting fitness program, session 1 was more for getting a 
good gauge of your fitness level. So I'll have my self some nice initial 
statistics of how bad my shape is from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In respect to the people who created the program I was following, I wouldn't 
get into details of the exercises I did. The exercises are free though, its 
just that the &lt;a href="http://www.fitnessblender.com"&gt;Fitness Blender&lt;/a&gt; team compiled 
and selected videos from their website to turn it into a proper fitness 
program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week 1 went smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;week 1 stats &lt;em&gt;(Jan 6-10, 2014)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sit &amp;amp; Reach: -18.4cm&lt;br /&gt;
Mile Run/Walk: 14m 57s&lt;br /&gt;
Full pushups: 15&lt;br /&gt;
Squats: 33&lt;br /&gt;
Full plank: 50s  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weight: 68kg&lt;br /&gt;
Neck: 36.7cm&lt;br /&gt;
Waist: 88.3cm  &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="fitness"></category></entry><entry><title>4 weeks to fitness experiment</title><link href="http://mattlebrun.com/4-weeks-to-fitness-experiment.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-02T17:48:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:mattlebrun.com,2014-01-02:4-weeks-to-fitness-experiment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A healthy programmer, is an effective programmer.&lt;br /&gt;
- me (when deciding to write this post)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my key goals for this year is to get in to the habit of keeping myself 
healthy. I believe its in our best interest as software engineers to have a 
balanced lifestlye to ensure that we are always working to the best of our 
abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since April of last year I've started feeling my way towards adding regular 
exercises as part of my weekly activities. I make sure that I do something to 
get my blood pumping at least once a week. While I've not been emperically 
tracking the effects of these efforts, It just feels good to get some 
adrenaline rush every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side note, my body fat percentage did became normal which was a first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I decided to take things up a notch for this month in the efforts of 
making this habit stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be following a 
&lt;a href="http://www.lulu.com/shop/daniel-segars-and-kelli-segars/low-impact-4-week-fat-loss-program-for-beginners/ebook/product-21250586.html"&gt;4-week program&lt;/a&gt; 
set up by the awesome folks at &lt;a href="http://www.fitnessblender.com/"&gt;Fitness Blender&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be doing a weekly update of my progress here and see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="fitness"></category></entry><entry><title>so long 2013, thanks for all the fish!</title><link href="http://mattlebrun.com/so-long-2013.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:mattlebrun.com,2014-01-01:so-long-2013.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another year has been shaved off of my remaining years of existence and its 
high time to reflect on all of my experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;tl;dr&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2013 was a year filled with unexpected, yet pleasant turn of events.
A lot of milestones have been reached earlier than expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the long version...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;save22&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last April I joined the engineering team of Save22. My growth as an engineer 
has really took off to a whole new level. I never had a chance to work with an 
engineering team as passionate and awesome. It's contagious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its interesting to note that the company's registered name is BOB FTW, where 
BOB stands for &lt;em&gt;Band of Brothers&lt;/em&gt;. We do live up to the name and its spirit. 
I'm really thankful for all the experiences and friends I've gained there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I hope to bring in more contribution to the success of our company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;family diner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've moved into a more cost-effective home/biz place. Its a 2-storey house 
where we've turned the 1st floor into the diner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The family food business has been doing well early 2013 however things have 
been quite challenging towards the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, our hopes remain high for this year. My plan is to find management 
seminars usually organized by Hapinoy and GoNegosyo or any other community 
where we can get ideas on how to take the family biz to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;python.ph, inc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Python Users Group Philippines has come a long way. 2013 is a milestone. 
Together with a group of core volunteers, we've incorporated our small group as 
a non-profit organization duly recognized by the Philippine government and the 
&lt;a href="http://www.python.org/psf/"&gt;Python Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our mission: To promote the Python programming language and to facilitate the 
growth of our local community of professionals and enthusiasts while hoping to 
make a small dent of improvement to the Philippine IT industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-founding and running a non-profit organization takes a lot of dedication and 
drive. I'm really lucky to be around this group of awesome folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This organization is very dear to me. Not only because its my first time to 
undertake something like this, but also because its been one of my long-term 
dreams to build a foundation similar to this. In a way, I'd like to believe 
that this is a granted wish from the heavens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;secret projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2013 served as the breeding ground for the idea behind our secret project to 
solidify. This year the goal is to set the initial stages in motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;padlamat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owning a home is waaay down our bucket list however when an opportunity was 
presented to Ela and I, we just had to take it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ela and I got ourselves a pre-selling studio condo in the Ayala Group's 
&lt;a href="http://www.avidaland.com/Avida-towers-asten.php"&gt;Avida Asten&lt;/a&gt; project in 
Makati. We would've went for a 1-bedroom unit had our budgets permitted. This 
takes a significant cut from our wedding savings fund but in any case, we are 
very happy with this humble abode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're now looking forward to the 2017 turnover of &lt;em&gt;padlamat&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;parting thoughts and on to 2014&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, 2013 has really been the most eventful year yet. Most of the things 
that have happened are but a starting point so I'm expecting challenges to come 
this year. If anything, I'm actually looking forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 here we go!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>good habits: the root cause in turning your dreams into reality</title><link href="http://mattlebrun.com/good-habits.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-23T15:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:mattlebrun.com,2012-09-23:good-habits.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I attended a dream boarding workshop with Mickey last September 22. What I 
thought to be just a day of fulfilling &lt;em&gt;"boyfriend duties"&lt;/em&gt;, turned out 
quite amazing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a realization. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you didn't know; dream boarding is when you put visual 
representation of your goals, desires, ambitions, dreams or what have you 
in a piece of card board &lt;em&gt;(best on an illustration board).&lt;/em&gt; The idea is 
that, these images becomes a mantra or a cue. Something that you can focus 
on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the workshop activities were timebound and the board we used is small 
(1/8 illustration board), we were forced to prioritize what to put on the 
board. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This got me thinking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are the most important goals do I have in the next couple of years or 
the next few months even? Then I realized that what I really need is to 
improve myself further. And how do I do that? Form better habits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe much of what we wanted to achieve in life may just be a byproduct of 
having good habits. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="thoughts"></category></entry><entry><title>why you don't need to know everything right away</title><link href="http://mattlebrun.com/you-dont-need-to-know-everything.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-18T15:30:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:mattlebrun.com,2012-09-18:you-dont-need-to-know-everything.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Learning and researching about a new technology or problem area is a very 
exciting activity for programmers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curiosity, for a programmer, is like an insatiable impulse. An unquenchable 
thirst. You take your time as you browse through one information to 
another. Consuming content after content. This can span from hours to days 
or longer. Your desire to "know more" drives you like a mad man. But when 
you're doing this during the course of a client project this can be a 
problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href="http://www.searchoptmedia.com/5-reasons-to-try-agile-in-your-next-software-project"&gt;Agile's&lt;/a&gt; 
key principle of simplicity. It gives emphasis on the simplest solution the 
would meet the requirements that best reflects your current knowledge on 
the technology and problem area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Applying that in this context: 
&lt;strong&gt;You don't need to know everything right away.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust that the deeper you go into the project, your knowledge and 
experience increases as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your clients simply can't afford a prolonged or delayed release and neither 
will you have that sense of accomplishment from actually shipping 
something. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do you deal with your insatiable curiosity? &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="agile"></category><category term="productivity"></category></entry><entry><title>hello world! v2.0: reflections on leaving the 9-5 life</title><link href="http://mattlebrun.com/leaving-9-to-5.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-17T21:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:mattlebrun.com,2012-09-17:leaving-9-to-5.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My recent move to finally join &lt;em&gt;(full-time)&lt;/em&gt; the tech start-up scene made me 
reflect once again on this topic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I've just stepped into the "unknown abyss" that we call the 
entrepreneurial road where a steady monthly paycheck is out of the 
question. This is quite a big leap for someone who &lt;em&gt;-- like a lot of people --&lt;/em&gt; 
have mouths to feed, debts to pay, and a family to support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &lt;em&gt;-- again, like a lot of people --&lt;/em&gt; I have plans for the future, 
passions to pursue, a purpose to fullfil, and I'm not getting any younger. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I made the jump nonetheless. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy actually. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just close your eyes, hold your breathe, and brace yourself for the roller 
coaster ride! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so fast friend! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't just went for it. If I did I would've faltered off the bat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was preparing my heart for years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my heart was ready, I've talked to the people I cared about for 
support. Then, when I finally got their &lt;em&gt;(hesitant)&lt;/em&gt; blessing that's the 
time I made the jump. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, there's a reason why even a faint sense of responsibility is 
required for this: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who care about you are affected the most in every decision or path 
you take. If you care about them too, you won't feel there's any point in 
your undertakings if you don't have them to share your ups and downs. It'll 
be one lonely roller coaster ride indeed. &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="startup"></category></entry><entry><title>don't waste time, it's more scarce than you think!</title><link href="http://mattlebrun.com/dont-waste-time.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-26T18:30:00+08:00</updated><author><name>matt lebrun</name></author><id>tag:mattlebrun.com,2012-07-26:dont-waste-time.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you say "yes" to others, make sure you are not saying "no" to 
yourself.
- Paulo Coelho&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I've been reminded of my struggle for having ownership with my work. 
A puzzle that I've finally solved after reaching a crossroad in my career. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've realized that when you're just doing your job or joined a company for 
the money, you're not only short-changing yourself, you're also doing it to 
the organization. If you're like me, who always makes sure you got your end 
covered so as not to drag people down, you'll probably feel bad about doing 
this intentionally or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recalling my previous work experiences; Yes I was challenged, excited, 
learned and shared new things, met new people, and I grew my skills set. 
But I never felt I owned the things I've done nor the projects I've 
launched. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point it just felt mechanical &lt;em&gt;-- input given, output delivered.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No extra-mile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No flowery, feel good, &lt;em&gt;if-I-blew-this-I'll-feel-like-shit-the-next-day&lt;/em&gt; 
effect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always ask the question, "To what end am I doing this?". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usual &lt;em&gt;(and wrong)&lt;/em&gt; answer: For the money. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I never really identified with the organizations I've joined in the 
past. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I didn't get the chance to work on things that aligned with my 
strong points. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But whatever the reason is, once you've realized these things it's time to 
stay true to yourself and others. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change your attitude or leave the job if you have to &lt;em&gt;(or both)&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just be sure you're not just doing it for the money &lt;em&gt;-- or you just 
momentarily have to as part of a grander purpose.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do it for love and passion instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dear friend always reminds me that the money always comes after. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Again:&lt;/strong&gt; Don't waste time, it's more scarce than you think!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="thoughts"></category></entry></feed>